Register of the Poland. Ministerstwo Informacji i Dokumentacji Records, 1939-1945
Hoover Institution Archives
- POLISH DIPLOMATIC OUTPOSTS, 1939-1945
  - India - Poland. Konsulat Generalny (Bombay). Correspondence
    - 1939-1942 (Folder 8)
    - 1943 (Folder 9)
    - 1944 (Folder 10)
  - Iran - Poland. Poselstwo (Iran)
    - Correspondence, 1943
      - January-May (Folder 11)
      - June-September (Box 43., Folder 1)
      - October-December (Folder 2)
    - Telegrams
      - 1941-1942 (Folder 3)
      - 1943-1944 (Folder 4)
  - Iraq - Poland. Poselstwo (Iraq). Correspondence, notes, articles from Bagdad press, 1943 (Folder 5)
  - Ireland - Poland. Konsulat Generalny (Dublin). Corres- (Folder 6)
  - pondence, 1941-1943
  - Italy
    - Poland. Ambasada (Italy). Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Folder 7)
    - Poland. Konsulat (Trieste). Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Folder 8)
  - Japan - Poland. Ambasada (Japan). Correspondence
    - 1940 (Box 44., Folder 1)
    - 1941 (Folder 2)
  - Lebanon - Poland. Konsulat Generalny (Beirut)
    - Correspondence, 1941-1944 (Folder 3)
    - Press reviews, 1944 (Folder 4)
  - Mexico - Poland. Poselstwo (Mexico)
    - Correspondence
      - 1939-1941 (Folder 5)
      - 1941-1942 (Folder 6)
      - 1943 (Folder 7)
    - Decoded telegrams, 1944 (Folder 8)
  - New Zealand - Poland. Konsulat Generalny (Wellington), Correspondence
    - 1941 (Folder 9)
    - 1943 (Folder 10)
  - Palestine
    - Poland. Konsulat Generalny (Jerusalem)
      - Correspondence
        - 1940-1942 (Box 45., Folder 1)
        - 1943 (Folder 2)
      - Telegrams
        - 1943
          - January-March (Folder 3)
          - April-June (Folder 4)
          - July-August (Folder 5)
        - 1944
          - January-March (Folder 6)
          - April-September (Folder 7)
    - Poland. Konsulat Generalny (Tel-Aviv). Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Folder 8)
  - Peru - Poland. Poselstwo (Peru). Correspondence, 1943-1944 (Box 46., Folder 1)
  - Romania - Poland. Ambasada (Romania)
    - Bulletin, 1940 April-May (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Folder 3)
    - Report. "South Eastern Poland Under Soviet Occupation," by A. Ciolkosz, 1939 December (Folder 4)
  - Soviet Union - Poland. Ambasada (Soviet Union)
    - General
      - Correspondence
        - 1941 (Folder 5)
        - 1942 (Folder 6)
        - 1943 (Folder 7)
      - Reports on Polish adults and children deported to the Soviet Union (Folder 8)
      - Telegrams from Polish deportees to Ambassador Kot, 1943 May 3 (Folder 9)
    - Social Welfare Department
      - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 47., Folder 1)
      - Maps (Folder 2)
      - Reports
        - Delegatury (Outposts/Stations) for Polish deportees
          - Arrest of Embassy's representatives, 1942 (Folder 3)
          - Chkalov (Folder 4)
          - Krasnoiarsk (Folder 5)
          - Liquidation of, 1942 (Folder 6-8)
        - Finances, 1942 (Folder 9)
        - Kolyma (Box 48., Folder 1)
        - Polish deportees (Folder 2)
  - Spain - Poland. Poselstwo (Spain). Corres- (Folder 3)
  - pondence, 1941-1944
  - Sweden - Poland. Poselstwo (Sweden)
    - Clippings from Danish, Finnish, and Swedish press, 1943 (Folder 4)
  - Sweden - Poland. Poselstwo (Sweden) (Contd.)
    - Correspondence
      - 1941-1942 (Folder 5)
      - 1943
        - January-February (Folder 6)
        - March (Folder 7)
        - April (Box 49., Folder 1-2)
        - May (Folder 3-4)
        - June (Folder 5-7)
        - August (Folder 8)
        - September (Folder 9)
        - October (Box 50., Folder 1-2)
        - November (Folder 3-4)
        - November-December (Folder 5)
      - 1944-1945 (Folder 6)
    - Decoded telegrams, 1943-1944 (Folder 7)
  - Switzerland - Poland. Poselstwo (Switzerland)
    - Correspondendce, 1942-1943 (Folder 8)
    - Decoded telegrams, 1942-1944 (Box 51., Folder 1)
    - Information bulletin, 1943 August-October (Folder 2)
  - Turkey
    - Poland. Ambasada (Turkey)
      - Correspondence
        - 1939-1940 (Folder 3)
        - 1941-1942 (Folder 4)
        - 1943 (Folder 5)
        - 1944 (Folder 6)
      - Manuscript by Stefan Werner entitled "Polonya," 1943 (Folder 7)
    - Poland. Konsulat Generalny (Istanbul)
      - Bulletins
        - Bulletin polonais, 1941 May-October (Folder 8)
        - La Pologne sous l'occupation allemande et sovietique, 1941-1943 (Folder 9)
        - Polska pod Okupacja Niemiecka i Sowiecka, 1941-1943 (Folder 10)
      - Correspondence
        - 1941-1942 (Box 52., Folder 1)
        - 1943
          - January-May (Folder 2)
          - June-August (Folder 3)
      - Decoded telegrams, 1943-1944 (Folder 4)
  - United States
    - Poland. Ambasada (United States)
      - Correspondence
        - 1939 (Folder 5)
        - 1940
          - February-July (Folder 6)
          - August-October (Folder 7)
          - November-December (Folder 8)
        - 1941
          - January-February (Folder 9)
          - February (Box 53., Folder 1)
          - March (Folder 2)
          - April (Folder 3)
          - May-June (Folder 4)
          - July-August (Folder 5)
          - September-December (Folder 6)
        - 1942 (Folder 7)
        - 1943
          - January-March (Folder 8)
          - April-May (Box 54., Folder 1)
          - June-July (Folder 2)
          - August-October (Folder 3)
          - November-December (Folder 4)
        - 1944 January-October (Folder 5)
      - Decoded telegrams, 1943 January-July (Folder 6)
      - Memoranda, notes, reports, 1941 (Folder 7)
      - Press reports, 1941
        - August (Box 55., Folder 1)
        - September (Folder 2-3)
        - October (Folder 4)
        - November (Folder 5)
    - Poland. Konsulat (Detroit). Correspondence, 1943 (Folder 6)
    - Poland. Konsulat (Pittsburg). Correspondence
      - 1940 (Folder 7)
      - 1941 (Box 56., Folder 1)
      - 1942 (Folder 2)
      - 1943
        - January-June (Folder 3)
        - July-December (Folder 4)
    - Poland. Konsulat (San Francisco). Correspondence, 1942 (Folder 5)
    - Poland. Konsulat Generalny (Chicago)
      - Bulletin entitled Polish War Relief, 1943 (Folder 6)
      - Clippings
        - American press, 1943 (Folder 7)
        - Polish-American press, 1941 (Box 57., Folder 1)
      - Correspondence
        - 1940 (Folder 2)
        - 1941
          - January-March (Folder 3)
          - April-May (Folder 4)
          - June-August (Folder 5)
          - September-December (Folder 6)
        - 1942
          - January-July (Folder 7)
          - August-September (Folder 8)
          - October-December (Box 58., Folder 1)
        - 1943
          - January-March (Folder 2)
          - April (Folder 3)
          - May (Folder 4)
          - June (Folder 5)
          - July (Folder 6)
          - August-September (Folder 7)
          - October (Box 59., Folder 1)
          - November-December (Folder 2)
        - 1944
          - January-February (Folder 3)
          - March-September (Folder 4)
    - Poland. Konsulat Generalny (New York)
      - Correspondence
        - 1940-1941 (Folder 5)
        - 1942 (Folder 6)
        - 1943
          - January-April (Folder 7)
          - May-September (Box 60., Folder 1)
          - October-December (Folder 2)
      - Decoded telegrams
        - 1943 (Folder 3)
        - 1944 (Folder 4)
      - Press reports, 1942-1943 (Folder 5)
  - Uruguay - Poland. Poselstwo (Uruguay). Decoded telegrams, 1943-1944 (Folder 6)
- POLISH ARMED FORCES, 1940-1944
  - General
    - Diary of an officer in the Polish armed forces in the Soviet Union, 1941-1942 (Box 60., Folder 7)
    - Financial records, 1941, 1942 (Box 61., Folder 1)
    - Reports of Polish paratroopers, 1942-1944
      - General (Folder 2)
      - Bialystok Province (Folder 3)
      - Lwow Province (Folder 4)
      - Nowogorodzk Province (Folder 5)
      - Stanislawow Province (Folder 6)
      - Tarnopol Province (Folder 7)
      - Wilno Province (Folder 8)
      - Wolyn Province (Box 62., Folder 1)
  - Poland. Polskie Sily Zbrojne (Polish Armed Forces). Correspondence, memoranda, reports, clippings, and printed matter
    - General
      - 1940-1942 (Folder 2)
      - 1943 (Folder 3)
    - Great Britain
      - 1940-1941 (Folder 4)
      - 1941-1942 (Folder 5)
      - 1942 (Folder 6)
      - 1943 (Folder 7)
      - 1944 (Box 63., Folder 1)
  - Poland. Polskie Sily Zbrojne (Polish Armed Forces). Correspondence, memoranda, reports, clippings, and printed matter (Contd.)
    - Sikorski, Wladyslaw (Prime Minister, Polish Government-in-Exile, 1939-1943; General, Commander-in-Chief, Polish Armed Forces, 1939-1943)
      - General
        - 1940-1941 (Folder 2)
        - 1942 (Folder 3)
      - Gibraltar catastrophe, 1943 July (Folder 4-5)
      - Gibraltar catastrophe, 1943 July (Box 64., Folder 1-3)
      - Middle East inspection tour, 1943 May-June (Folder 4)
  - Poland. Polskie Sily Zbrojne. Armia Polska w ZSSR (Polish Army in the USSR). Correspondence, memoranda, reports, clippings, and printed matter
    - Anders, Wladyslaw (General, Commanding Officer, Polish Army in the USSR, 1941-1942; Commander-in-Chief, Polish Army, Middle, 1942-1943) (Folder 5)
    - Citizenship and passports for Poles in the Soviet Union, 1941-1943 (Folder 6)
    - Deportees
      - General, 1943-1944 (Box 65., Folder 1-2)
      - Military, 1941-1942 (Folder 3)
    - Evacuation to Iran
      - 1942-1943 (Folder 4)
      - 1943 (Folder 5)
    - Prisoners of war camps (Folder 6)
  - Poland. Polskie Sily Zbrojne. Marynarka Wojenna (Polish Navy), 1940-1943. Correspondence, memoranda, reports (Folder 7)
  - Poland. Polskie Sily Zbrojne. Polskie Sily Powietrzne (Polish Air Force) (Great Britain). Memoranda, reports, notes
    - 1940-1941 (Box 66., Folder 1)
    - 1942 (Folder 2)
    - 1943 (Folder 3)
- POLISH PRESS AGENCY (PARIS), 1939-1943
  - General
    - Bulletins
      - Bulletin hebdomadaire, 1940 January, May (Box 66., Folder 4)
      - Les Polonais sur le continent, 1941 June-August (Folder 5)
      - Presse allemande, 1941 June-August (Folder 6)
      - Presse parisienne, 1941 June-August (Folder 7)
      - Revue de presse, 1940 May (Box 67., Folder 1)
    - Correspondence and reports
      - 1939-1940 July (Folder 2)
      - 1940
        - August-September (Folder 3)
        - October (Folder 4)
        - November-December (Folder 5)
    - Press reports
      - 1940 (Folder 6)
      - 1941
        - January-February (Box 68., Folder 1)
        - February (Folder 2)
        - March (Folder 3)
        - March-April (Folder 4)
        - April-May (Folder 5)
        - May-June (Folder 6)
        - July (Folder 7)
        - August (Box 69., Folder 1)
        - September (Folder 2)
        - October (Folder 3)
        - November (Folder 4)
        - December (Folder 5)
      - 1942 (Folder 6-7)
      - 1943
        - March-April (Folder 8)
        - April (Folder 9)
    - Press reviews
      - French press
        - 1940 (Box 70., Folder 1)
        - 1941
          - January-July (Folder 2)
          - August-December (Folder 3)
      - Italian press, 1941-1942 (Folder 4)
  - Jerusalem Branch
    - Bulletins, 1943
      - April (Folder 5)
      - May (Folder 6)
      - June-July (Folder 7)
      - August-September (Box 71., Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1943 (Folder 2)
    - Polish radio broadcasts, 1943 (Folder 3)
- POLISH RESEARCH CENTER (JERUSALEM), 1943-1944
  - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 71., Folder 4)
  - Memoranda, notes, reports, 1943 (Folder 5-6)
- POLISH INFORMATION CENTER (NEW YORK), 1940-1944
  - Bulletins
    - General, 1942 (Box 71., Folder 7)
    - Biuletyn Polski
      - 1941
        - September (Box 72., Folder 1)
        - October (Folder 2)
        - November (Folder 3)
        - December (Folder 4)
      - 1942
        - January (Folder 5)
        - February (Folder 6)
        - March (Box 73., Folder 1)
        - April (Folder 2)
        - May (Folder 3)
        - June (Folder 4)
        - July (Folder 5)
        - August (Folder 6)
        - September (Box 74., Folder 1)
        - October (Folder 2)
        - November (Folder 3)
        - December (Folder 4)
      - 1943
        - January (Folder 5)
        - February (Folder 6)
        - March (Folder 7)
    - Le Bulletin polonais, 1942 (Folder 8)
    - A News Bulletin on East European Affairs, 1940-1942 (Box 75., Folder 1)
    - Przeglad Tygodniowy Polskiej Katolickiej Agencji Prasowej, 1942 (Folder 2)
    - Tygodniowy Przeglad Literacki Kola Pisarzy z Polski, 1942
      - January (Folder 3)
      - February-March (Folder 4)
      - April (Folder 5)
      - June-July (Folder 6)
      - August-September (Folder 7)
      - October-November (Folder 8)
    - "Tygodniowy Serwis Literacki Kola Pisarzy z Polski," 1941 November-December (Folder 9)
- POLISH INFORMATION CENTER (NEW YORK)
  - Correspondence
    - 1940 April-December (Box 76., Folder 1)
    - 1941
      - January-April (Folder 2)
      - May-June (Folder 3)
      - July-August (Folder 4)
      - September-December (Folder 5)
    - 1942 (Folder 6)
    - 1942-1943 (Folder 7)
    - 1943
      - January-March (Box 77., Folder 1)
      - April-May (Folder 2)
      - June (Folder 3)
      - July (Folder 4)
      - August (Folder 5)
      - October-November (Box 78., Folder 1)
      - December (Folder 2)
    - 1944 (Folder 3)
  - Decoded telegrams
    - 1943 May-December (Folder 4)
    - 1944
      - January-February (Folder 5)
      - March-April (Folder 6)
  - Reports
    - General
      - 1940-1941 (Box 79., Folder 1)
      - 1942 (Folder 2)
      - 1943 (Folder 3)
    - Report to General Sikorski on the work of the Polish Information Center in New York, by Burnet Hershey, 1942 (Folder 4-5)
- POLAND, 1938-1945.
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, notes, clippings, printed matter and other material.
  - Foreign relations
    - Czechoslovakia
      - General
        - 1938 (Box 79., Folder 6)
        - 1940-1941 (Box 80., Folder 1)
        - 1941 (Folder 2)
        - 1942 (Folder 3)
        - 1943 (Folder 4)
      - British press, 1941-1942 (Folder 5)
      - Emigre government, 1944 (Folder 6)
      - Slovakia, 1941 (Box 81., Folder 1)
    - Germany
      - 1940-1941 (Folder 2)
      - 1941 (Folder 3)
      - 1942 (Folder 4)
      - 1942-1943 (Folder 5)
      - 1944-1945 (Box 82., Folder 1)
      - 1941 (Folder 2)
      - 1942-1943 (Folder 3)
    - Soviet Union
      - General
        - Undated (Folder 4)
        - 1941
          - August-September (Folder 5)
          - October-December (Folder 6)
        - 1942
          - January-February (Box 83., Folder 1)
          - March-April (Folder 2)
          - May (Folder 3)
          - June-July (Folder 4)
          - August-September (Folder 5)
          - October-November (Folder 6)
          - November-December (Box 84., Folder 1)
        - 1943
          - January-February (Folder 2)
          - March (Folder 3)
          - April-May (Folder 4)
          - June-August (Folder 5)
          - September-October (Box 85., Folder 1)
          - November-December (Folder 2)
      - Soviet anti-Polish propaganda, 1943 (Folder 3)
    - Ukraine
      - 1940-1941 (Folder 4)
      - 1941 (Folder 5)
      - 1942-1945 (Folder 6)
  - History - Occupation, 1939-1945
    - General
      - General
        - 1940-1941 (Box 86., Folder 1)
        - 1941 (Folder 2-3)
      - Diplomatic correspondence and reports, 1939-1940 (Folder 4)
      - Letters from Poland, 1939-1940 (Folder 5)
      - Military reports
        - 1939 (Box 87., Folder 1)
        - 1940
          - January-February (Folder 2)
          - March (Folder 3-4)
      - Press clippings
        - 1939-1940 (Folder 5)
        - 1940-1941 (Folder 6)
        - 1941 (Box 88., Folder 1)
        - 1942-1943 (Folder 2)
        - 1943 (Folder 3-4)
      - Reports
        - General
          - 1939 (Folder 5)
          - 1939-1940 (Folder 6)
          - 1939-1940 (Box 89., Folder 1-2)
          - 1942 (Folder 3)
        - Military reports
          - 1940
            - April (Folder 4)
            - May (Folder 5)
            - September (Folder 6)
            - December (Folder 7)
          - 1941
            - January (Folder 8)
            - February (Folder 9)
            - March (Box 90., Folder 1)
            - May (Folder 2)
            - August (Folder 3)
            - October-December (Folder 4)
        - Press reports, 1941-1942 (Folder 5)
        - Statements of British and French governments, 1939 (Folder 6)
    - German occupation
      - Clippings
        - General
          - 1940-1941 (Folder 7)
          - 1942-1943 (Box 91., Folder 1)
        - Agriculture, 1940-1943 (Folder 2)
        - Cities
          - Gdynia, Gdansk, Pomorze (Folder 3)
          - Krakow (Folder 4-5)
          - Lodz, Lublin, Przemysl (Folder 6)
          - Poznan, Lodz (Box 92., Folder 1)
          - Teshin and Upper Silesia (Folder 2)
          - Warsaw (Folder 3)
        - Concentration camps (Folder 4)
        - Culture and science (Folder 5)
        - Deportations (Folder 6)
        - Economic conditions, 1941-1943 See also Agriculture (Folder 7)
        - Food supply, 1940-1943 (Box 93., Folder 1)
        - German minorities in Poland (Folder 2)
        - Health conditions, 1941-1943 (Folder 3)
        - Poles in the German Army (Folder 4)
        - Polish workers in Germany (Folder 5)
        - Resistance
          - 1941-1943 (Folder 6)
          - 1943 (Folder 7)
        - Terror and persecution (Box 94., Folder 1-3)
        - Women and children (Folder 4)
      - Currency (Folder 5)
      - Orders, decrees
        - 1939 (Box 95., Folder 1)
        - 1940-1942 (Folder 2)
      - Reports
        - General
          - 1939-1940 (Folder 3)
          - 1940 (Folder 4-6)
          - 1940-1943 (Box 96., Folder 1)
        - Agriculture, forestry (Folder 2)
        - Commerce, financial institutions (Folder 3-4)
        - Deportations to Germany (Folder 5)
        - Economic conditions (Folder 6)
        - German minorities in Poland (Folder 7)
        - German press and propaganda (Box 97., Folder 1-3)
        - Rationing (Folder 4)
        - Working conditions (Folder 5-6)
      - Subject file
        - Church and religion
          - 1939-1940 (Folder 7)
          - 1940 (Folder 8)
          - 1940 (Box 98., Folder 1)
        - Concentration camps, 1939-1941 (Folder 2)
        - Gdansk, Gdynia, 1939-1940 (Folder 3)
        - German Fifth Column, 1940 (Folder 4-5)
        - Jews, Persecution of, 1939-1941 (Folder 6)
        - Persecutions, repressions, terror
          - 1939 (Folder 7)
          - 1940 (Folder 8)
          - 1940 (Box 99., Folder 1)
        - Polish prisoners of war in Germany, 1940 (Folder 2)
        - Polish underground outposts, 1940 (Folder 3)
        - Social welfare, 1940 (Folder 4)
      - Writings
        - General (Folder 5-7)
        - General (Box 100., Folder 1-5)
        - Persecution of Jews (Box 101., Folder 1)
    - Soviet occupation
      - General
        - Clippings
          - General, 1940 (Folder 2)
          - Polish emigre press, 1940-1943 (Folder 3)
          - Pravda
            - 1939-1940 (Folder 4-5)
            - 1940 (Folder 6)
        - Documents from the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1939-1945 (Box 102., Folder 1)
        - Excerpts from the Soviet press (Folder 2)
        - Index to Soviet newspaper articles, 1939 (Folder 3)
        - Leaflets (Folder 4)
        - Radio broadcasts, transcripts, 1940 (Folder 5)
        - Reports
          - General. Miscellaneous reports relating to Soviet aggression, 1939-1940, and one relating to Soviet nationalities (Folder 6)
          - "The Military and Political Situation on the Eve of Soviet Aggression," n.d. (Folder 7)
          - "The Alleged Incorporation of the Polish Eastern Provinces in the Soviet Union," London, 1943 (Folder 8)
          - "The Alleged Incorporation of the Polish Eastern Provinces in the Soviet Union," London, 1943 (Box 103., Folder 1)
          - "The Soviet War of Agression and the Annexation of Polish Territories in 1939", London, 1943 (Folder 2)
        - Writings
          - "Poland's Case" by Major Guy Lloyd, n.d. (Folder 3)
          - "Russia Versus Poland" by Captain Strumph-Wojtkiewicz, 1942 (Folder 4)
          - "Ziemie wschodnie Polski pod okupacja sowiecky" by J. Laskowski, 1942 (Folder 5)
          - "Dzialnosc Zwiazku Sowieckiego na ternie okupowanych ziem Polski" by Dr. Zdzislaw Lecki, 1943 (Folder 6)
          - "Polska a Litwa" by Professor Wielkowski, 1943 (Folder 7)
          - "Soviet Economic Policy in the Occupied Part of Poland, 1939-1941," London, 1943 (Folder 8)
      - Eastern Poland
        - General (Folder 9)
        - Annexation by the USSR, 1939-1941 (Folder 10)
        - Belorussia, 1939-1940 (Folder 11)
        - Belorussia, 1939-1940 (Box 104., Folder 1)
        - Deportations (Folder 2)
        - Education, 1939-1941 (Folder 3)
        - Elections and voting (Folder 4-5)
        - Incorporation into the USSR, 1939 (Folder 6-7)
        - Population policy, 1942 (Folder 8)
        - Population policy, 1942 (Box 105., Folder 1)
        - Wilno
          - 1939-1941 (Folder 2-7)
          - 1940-1941 (Box 106., Folder 1)
        - Wilno University, 1939 (Folder 2)
      - Southeastern Poland
        - General (Folder 3-4)
        - Arrests of local population, 1939-1940 (Folder 5)
        - Catholic Church, persecution of clergy, 1939-1940 (Folder 6)
        - Deportations
          - General, 1940-1941 (Folder 7-8)
          - Clippings, 1941-1942 (Box 107., Folder 1)
          - Correspondence relating to (Folder 2)
          - Letters of deportees, Excerpts from (Folder 3)
          - Memoirs of deportees
            - General (excerpts) (Folder 4)
            - "Compulsory Refuge: A Few Memories," 1944 (Folder 5)
            - "A Journey to Soviet Siberia" by Countess Czarkowska-Golejewska, 1944 (Folder 6)
          - Writings
            - "Deportations From Soviet-Occupied Polish Territories," 1943 (Folder 7)
            - "Polacy w Zwiazku Sowieckim," 1944 (Folder 8)
        - Economic conditions
          - 1939-1940 (Box 108., Folder 1)
          - 1940 (Folder 2-3)
          - 1940-1941 (Folder 4)
        - Education, schools, libraries, 1939-1941 (Folder 5)
        - Elections, 1939-1940 (Folder 6)
        - Elections, 1939-1940 (Box 109., Folder 1)
        - Living conditions, 1940 (Folder 2)
        - Lwow
          - General (Folder 3)
          - National Assembly of Western Ukraine, 1939 October (Folder 4)
        - Minorities, 1940 (Folder 5-6)
        - Working conditions, 1939-1940 (Folder 7)
- POLES DEPORTED TO THE SOVIET UNION, 1939-1945
  - General
    - General (Box 110., Folder 1)
    - Diary of Alicija Korzeniowska, 1940 March-1941 December (Folder 2)
    - Identity records from the Social Welfare Department of the Polish Embassy in Moscow-Kuibyshev, 1942 March-June (Folder 3-6)
    - Identity records from the Social Welfare Department of the Polish Embassy in Moscow-Kuibyshev, 1942 March-June (Box 111., Folder 1-5)
    - Identity records from the Social Welfare Deparment of the Polish Embassy in Moscow-Kuibyshev, 1942 March-June (Box 112., Folder 1-6)
    - Identity records from the Social Welfare Department of the Polish Embassy in Moscow-Kuibyshev, 1942 March-June (Box 113., Folder 1)
    - Memoirs
      - General (Folder 2-3)
      - "At Exile in Kazachstan," n.d. (Folder 4)
      - "By the River Pieczora" by Lt. Machnik, n.d. (Folder 5)
      - "Chmury na horizoncie," n.d. (Folder 6)
      - Description of Czortkow Prison by Zenon Wcislo, n.d. (Folder 7)
      - "Moje sowieckie wiezienia i lagry" by Lucjan Blit, n.d. (Folder 8)
      - "Na Kolyme" by Teodozja Lisiewicz, n.d. (Folder 9)
      - "Na zsylce w Kazachstanie" by Janusz Jezierski, n.d. (Folder 10)
      - "Nieco o teorii I praktyce niektorych przepisow prawnych w ZSSR" by Stanislaw Lubodziecki, n.d. (Folder 11)
      - "Pod Sowiecka Inwazja," n.d. (Folder 12)